If you've been dreaming [music] of your
very own luxury home tucked away in the
trees on a halfacre lot [music] just
minutes from Lake Belton, you're going
to want to watch this video. Today, I'm
giving you a tour of one of Central
Texas's most beautiful and private
communities, [music] Rancho Delago. The
homes are stunning, the lots are huge,
and the lifestyle is unmatched. Hi
friends, [music] I'm Andrea Dudik, your
local real estate broker and relocation
guide. Every week I help people just
like you relocating [music] to and from
areas like Temple, Belton, Fedo, Harker
Heights, and all of the surrounding
areas. Today I'm giving you a tour of
[music] Rancho Delago here in Morgan's
Point Resort within Belton ISD just
minutes from the lake. [music] And hey,
if you are curious about living in
Morgans's Point Resort, I have a really
awesome [music] video over on my YouTube
that goes over the full parameters and
lifestyle of Morgan's Point. Let's get
started.
Okay, [music] friends, we are entering
the city of Morgan's Point Resort.
Wonderful. Welcome to Morgan's Point
Resort sign.
Love this little Morgan's Point Resort.
City limit population 3357. [music]
It makes it feel extra small, but it's
right here in Belton. [music]
As we enter the neighborhood, you'll
notice right away how peaceful and
private it feels.
Rancho Delago is built around mature
treats and um unlike a lot of most new
construction communities, it does not
feel cookie cutter. This community has
been here for a tiny bit. There are
different phases and they are still
obviously building in here. There are
plenty of lots, but I [music] am telling
you, it is so hard to find communities
like this one [music] where they're
leaving all of these beautiful mature
oak trees and building around [music]
them. Usually, you get those new
construction homes and you have to start
from the ground up in terms of getting
that mature landscaping. You don't here.
And unlike a lot of areas where there's
just a lot of cedar, you get these
mature oak trees, which is another
reason [music] I really, really love
Morgan's Point Resort. So, all of these
lots in here are on over a half acre,
[music] some even going up to 3/4 of an
acre. The price points here are
basically over 800,000 [music]
to I would say just under a million. But
this is just luxury at its finest.
[music] And I I love this neighborhood
and I love Morgan's Point. You can see
that all the neighbors feel really
[music] spaced out between each other.
And Rancho Delago is in the city of
[music] Morgan's Point Resort. You are
about 5 minutes to Lake Belton's boat
[music] ramps. There are multiple
locations um to access boating. You're
[music] just 12 minutes from HB on West
Adams, probably 10 to 12 minutes from HB
off of 317. [music]
You're 15 minutes to Baylor Scott and
White Hospital,
which that [music] one's a really big
one. Um, just where we are in location
to medical proximity. We get a lot of
people not only moving here to [music]
work with the health care systems but
you know people that need more frequent
or concern or are concerned about
needing more frequent medical care
wanting to [music] be close to the
hospital. So, you're still only about 15
minutes from Baylor, Scott, and White.
And there's actually a premier ER on
West [music] Adams that I have used
myself that I referred family members to
go to in [music] emergency because it's
like an ER. Uh, it's called Premier ER,
but they have an emergency side of it
and then as well as a
uh clinic side of [music] it. So you
don't have to wait in a hospital, but if
you need something quicker, just lots of
really, really [music] great medical
resources out here. But as you can see
as we drive around, there are lots of
little pockets and culde-sacs to still
build on. So while the builders are
doing speck homes, which means they've
already started some homes, you are
going to get better [music] deals and
lower cost with those speck homes. um
maybe even some more negotiation power
because they are trying to offload that
inventory. They're trying to get rid of
[music] their interest that they're
paying every month. Um you can still
build custom. I can help [music] with
both of those. Don't forget to
get a realtor when doing new
construction because they the um
builders do rep sorry the sales reps do
represent the builders and [music] their
best interest. And so, not that they're
illharmed, but you definitely want
someone advocating for you and they
don't give you price cuts for not using
a realtor.
Yeah, really [music] beautiful community
and we'll go ahead and give you a tour
of
out just outside [music] of this
community and all the surrounding areas.
All right, this is just a [music] brief
little tour of the surrounding area
outside of Rancho Delago. We are coming
up [music] to 317 which is that main
juncture through Belton. It also
connects to West Adams um
east and west through Temple. So very
[music]
centrally located if you are looking to
access down Belton or Temple.
If schools are important to [music] you,
Ra Rancho Delago is zoned for some of
the top performing campuses in Belton
[music]
ISD.
Um, right up here on the left, we have
Lake Belton High School.
So, the community zone for Lake Belton
High School. There are two high schools
in Belton. There's also um Belton High
School, more in Belton.
But this one's [music] newer. It's
beautiful. And then the community is
also zoned for North Belton Middle
School and High Point Elementary.
Other parts of
Morgan's [music] Point are zoned for
Lakewood Elementary. Both are fantastic.
And again, if you want information on
those school districts, you [music] can
head on over to beltonisd.org.
You can also head over to niche.com
[music]
and I think it's.com niche.com and get
some really great resources for the
school districts.
As far as tax rate, Rancho [music]
Delago sits at a 2.24
tax rate.
kind of everywhere in central Texas,
[music]
whether you're inside of city limits,
outside of city limits, you'll be
looking at anywhere from a 1.6 [music]
1.7 outside of city limits up to a 2.9%
tax rate depending on where you [music]
are. I have a really great video that I
did recently with Jacob Stutard at Edge
Finance [music] that talks about
property taxes in general and just some
different ways, well, I guess
understanding them and how they affect
your monthly payment, [music] but as
well as ways that you can reduce your
property taxes and taxable amount
[music] to save you some money. So, even
though our home prices are lower than a
lot of areas, our property taxes [music]
are a little bit higher than some
places. speak. We do not have a state
income tax. So, they [music] make up for
it in other ways and collecting with
those taxes.
But again, there are ways in terms
[music] of saving money with your
homestead exemption. If you are a
disabled veteran, there's exemptions for
that. Texas really takes care of [music]
their vets. And over 65 exemptions,
but all worth looking into.
So, [music] actually, let's go over. I'm
going to take you real quick over here.
So, on our right here, we [music] have
Backyard Barbecue. They have some of the
most amazing barbecue food. I eat there
a lot. I live in Morgan's Point,
actually. And there's only a couple
restaurants right [music] here in
Morgan's Point. One of them being
Backyard Barbecue and one of them being
right here, Soul Dealiscoco. Mexican
restaurant number four. Uh, but you are,
geez, being so close to West Adams and
um, Belin [music] off of 317, you're
still only 10 minutes away from other
restaurants if you want to venture a
little bit out from [music] these
restaurants.
One of the biggest reasons [music]
people love this area is lifestyle. You
are so close to [music] Belton Lake for
boating. Uh paddle boarding, fishing,
hiking, [music] swimming. You have
Morgan's Point Resort amenities. There's
uh I love Morgan's Point Park. That's a
[music] really great park. Got Cedar
Ridge Park.
Got a ton of parks [music] around here.
What's that other one right there? Um,
>> what's the splash park?
>> No,
the um Oh my gosh,
the park [music] right there in Morgan's
Point on the left. Like when you're
headed to go over the dam. [music] It's
on your left.
See the ridge? See the ridge?
They have a lot [music] of parks here.
but few different entrances [music]
to Rancho Delago, some of the more
established areas, and we're going to go
take you through [music] a couple new
construction communities. I'm sorry,
we're going to go take you through a
couple new construction homes.
Okay, I'm going to give you a tour of
two different floor plans today. This is
the Builder's Hoover floor plan. I just
stepped inside and the selections are so
pretty. They're very different. I think
you're going to love it. Um, both of
these homes that we're looking at today
are priced at 869,000. [music]
This is a 4 bed, three bath floor plan.
Um, just over 2,800 square ft on over
half acre lot. [music] I'm so excited.
Let's go.
The outside obviously is so pretty. They
do so good with their stone [music] and
stucco selections. They are in the
process of completing this home. It said
it's ready this month. I think they
could be probably end of this month.
Still have to get in saw and irrigation,
but there's no electricity [music] on.
So, we're going to hope that you can get
a good look at it even though there's no
lighting.
[music]
Well, this home is so pretty. Super
split floor plan. There's some things I
really, really, really love about the
design elements. So, this rounded
fireplace, we were just talking about
it. Not super common. I've never really
seen a rounded fireplace like that. It
just feels very upscale and elegant in
here. This builder also does a great job
with their windows [music] and lighting.
The ceilings are all very high in here.
Um, [music]
the selections are beautiful. You can
see we have these two-toned pendants and
light fixtures throughout. [music]
Um, this is all very rounded in here,
giving it a definitely a very different
look. [music] I would say very
modernized
feel, but they do. This is the kitchen.
Obviously, we have these uh like honey
oak cabinets, soft clothes, shaker
style. You'll have your [music]
microwave, oven, and stove. So, you'll
have your stove here and dishwasher.
Fridges [music] are not included, but
you know, always something we can try
and ask for for you. But you have your
sink over with this beautiful backsplash
overlooking [music] your main living
space and dining space. And of course,
views of [music] the backyard from every
angle with those mature oak trees. You
can see your outdoor covered patio and
kitchen. It's just very, very [music]
beautiful. And even without the the
light or the electricity on, you can get
a great feel [music]
of this home. Um, something I want to
take note of is actually the ceiling
work.
So, the beams in the kitchen are so
pretty.
Very modernized light fixtures,
pendants. I mean, all that really sets
this builder apart in their elegance.
If we even peek at the entryway and the
pretty chandelier with the woodwork in
the tray ceiling above it,
but this floor plan, so again, it is a
four bed, three bath. What's really,
really great, we'll start off on this
side. So, you have tile throughout here
on the flooring. You'll have carpet in
all of the bedrooms.
You have the primary suite off of the
main living space [music]
with the tray ceiling, recess lighting,
and overlooking
the backyard. And there will be carpet
in here.
This is where the lighting gets a little
tough, but we're going to try and do it.
You'll have a large soaking tub,
dual vanities.
You have a walkthrough closet and a
walkthrough shower. So, we're going to
go ahead and just do a little loopy
[music] in there for you.
[music] Sorry, I've been breathing so
extra heavy. Come on. This baby needs to
get out of here and it's going to be
evicted. But really cool walkthrough
shower. Pretty pretty tile selections,
lots of lighting. Builder always does a
fantastic job with their bathrooms and
kitchens. [music]
I'm always really impressed.
And you have your formal dining space
right off of the kitchen. Again,
overlooking the huge oversized [music]
backyard, which will be fully fenced,
but plenty of room to put in a pool if
you want to. So, this this floor plan, I
haven't toured this floor plan before.
Um, you have threecar garages on all of
these homes, but when you come in
through the garage, [music] you know,
you can carry in groceries into your
kitchen.
There's also your laundry space [music]
um with a utility sink,
tons [music] of cabinet space and space
for a refrigerator.
And then in the garage, you have your
threecar garage, pull down attic,
windows in the garage. That's great.
You know, someone's dirty, they can
strip down, put all their clothes in the
laundry room, carry groceries in. But
one of the features I really love is
that it's set up very mother-in-law
style slash whether you have like an,
you know, someone living with you, a
guest that really needs that privacy,
[music]
finding those floor plans that have the
full bath [music] connected to an
additional bedroom is very sought after,
but not super common. So, I love that
about this one because this whole area,
it's almost like a separate wing to the
home for privacy. So, it connects to a
full bath with a walk-in shower,
but if you have guests that need to
access that additional um [music]
bathroom, they don't have to use the
primary suite. They can access that off
of the kitchen.
And then on the other side
we have the additional two bedrooms.
[music] Um something again that really
sets it apart are these eight foot
doors. So anytime you have these really
tall doors, it really elevates [music]
and makes spaces feel elegant. So again,
this is going to be carpet in here. You
have a walk-in closet in all of the
secondary rooms.
Actually, I I guess I missed that. So
you have multiple closets. So there's
also a closet [music] in your Jack and
Jill. So these final bedrooms have a
Jack and Jill, a shared bathroom, but
private because there will be a door
here. So they each have their own vanity
and closet. They can close off,
come in, share a commode, your toilet,
and the tub shower.
Okay, so just that one extra bedroom has
an extra closet,
but really neat floor plan. Really
beautiful selections. And then we'll go
check out the backyard on this one
before we head on over to the second
floor plan.
So, you can kind of see in the backyard
how large this lot is. Just imagine
[music] to the end of where those fence
posts are, but super large. They'll be
very level, really pretty trees in your
yard and outside of [music] it. We do
get a ton of deer in Morgan's Point, so
extra [music] peaceful,
really huge outdoor patio. And then
you've got leathered granite out here,
which is pretty popular right now.
Really cool texture and fun. You'll have
a built-in grill, sink. I don't think
they include the outdoor refrigerator,
but maybe if you buy this house, I'll
buy you one. [music]
Put your beverages in. Outdoor
fireplace. Also little [music]
features like, you know, having
electricity already hooked up for your
[music] outdoor TV.
But all in all, really great. And of
course, it'll all be leveled out here.
You won't have this big step down, but
you can just imagine entertaining and
hanging out. It's [music] the most
beautiful day. We're January, are we the
second? January 2nd. And [music] I
actually don't even need this jacket.
It's We're hitting high 70s today, I
think. So, really pretty day here.
[music] Love to hear what you think of
this one. And then let leave a note in
the comments. Do you like house number
one? This one, the Hoover floor plan, or
the second one we check out. Let's go.
All right, we're on to house number two.
This is the builder's Castell floor
plan. You can see the elevation. The
[music] exterior of it is definitely
different. The first one had that stone
exterior, four-sided masonry, excuse me.
This one has the brick and siding
exterior in [music] the front. Uh, very
pretty, but very different look. And
this one has this beautiful overhanging
oak tree. Both are priced at867. [music]
Very similar square footages. I think
this one is just slightly [music]
bigger, but because it's a totally
different floor plan, the spacing feels
different. [music] This one is four bed,
three and a half bath. So, you have that
additional half bath. Um, and you also
have an additional dining [music] space.
So, some of the spaces might feel a
little bit smaller, but just very
different on depending on what your
needs and wants [music] are. So, one of
the things I noticed first was the last
one was those gold and [music] brass
fixtures. This one they stuck with the
black fixtures.
This is the formal dining space right
off of the entryway. Of course, you
could set it up as a home office or
something if you wanted to. Love the
accent wall. Really fun.
They did um I think more cooler tones in
this one. The last one was slightly
warmer.
And of course, they'll put in all of the
fixtures. They're probably about a month
out from this one as well, but the
kitchen completely different feel. The
the last one was um more of the brown
and warm tones. This has more of those
gray tone
cabinets.
You have a farmhouse sink, this center
island, [music] uh, quartz countertops
overlooking the
beautiful living space. I'll show you
that Florida to ceiling stone fireplace
in a minute, [music] but you'll have
your microwave on that side. I think
you'll have a double oven on this one.
And then your range over here. There is
gas in this community. So, not common in
all communities. This community does
have gas. [music] I always, it's funny,
I'll get people that reach out for my
videos and especially from the West
Coast, they're like, "We noticed you
mentioned gas." And I'm like, "It's a
priority for people that are used to
having it."
Huge pantry, huge butler pantry. Going
to have electrical throughout here. Um,
not very often you see [music] quartz
countertops in here. huge pantry and
tons of space if you want to put in
additional, you know, your [music]
additional appliances, whatnot in there.
But I think these will probably have
some glass windows [music] in the top
cabinets that would be really pretty in
here.
They've just started installing the
flooring. They have the interlocking
vinyl plank on this one. It's really
pretty. It's a
cool toned wood [music] look. And then
this amazing floor to ceiling stone
fireplace [music]
with the built-in shelves, the floating
shelves on each side. [music] Really,
really, really pretty. And then of
course that the the incredibly vated
ceiling with the wood beam running
through it, recessed lighting. It just
feels [music]
super open and inviting. And then you
have the um dining space right off of
the kitchen, which [music]
is kind of why you have those two dining
spaces. You can use that space upon
entry for dining if maybe you didn't
need as big of a space. You have one
here. This is a split floor plan. You
have your uh primary suite behind the
kitchen and your secondary
bedrooms on the other side of the home
beyond the living room. Again,
note that there are those 8ft doors.
Feels really [music] large. You have a
utility clo I'm sorry, a yeah, utility
closet. I think this is for your
internet and all of your hookups and
stuff there.
[music] And then we have lighting in on
some of the fixtures and not others just
yet. [music] So, we couldn't turn on
this space. Really beautiful accented
tray ceiling.
This overlooks your [music]
backyard. I do think there will be
carpet in here. [music]
Bathroom layout is totally different.
So, you have your dual vanities
split [music] amongst each side. A
really great soaking tub, a walk-in
shower. It's not your car wash style
shower that we saw in the last one, but
still very beautiful.
And then you also have split closets.
So, a little more divided and private. I
also really love that they're doing that
on both sides. Isn't this amazing?
Yeah, this closet is fantastic.
You always know too when you take people
through because
[music] the bougier spouse will always
say, "This is my closet." I'm like,
"Yeah, that'd be my closet, too." Okay.
And then we have the uh you have a half
bath, [music] which the last one didn't
have, but little half bath for guests
with some hexagon [music]
flooring, and then a really awesome
utility room, your wash um your laundry
space with a built-in utility sink,
space for a fridge, your washer dryer
hookups, and tons of cabinet space.
[music]
But I think it's really pretty. All
right. And then you also have your
threecar garage on this one.
All of these homes have the threecar
garages are standard.
The the tall doors.
The outdoor kitchens,
all standard.
And you'll hear me say I really love
about this builder. A lot of the things
they include standard are upgrades for
other builders.
So again, four bed, 3 and 1 half bath.
This is your second out of four bedroom
[music] and it's a Jack and Jill, but
you have really beautiful counters in
each of these spaces. I [music] think
they actually might be granite, but they
have a very quartz-like feel,
but you have a shared
bathroom [music] with separate vanities,
walk-in closets in both. Now, this
builder, their bedrooms always feel a
[music] little bit smaller to me. So, if
bedroom sizes are super important to
you, I can always get you specific
measurements. And then this is the
[music] third of the fourth bedrooms.
And this one is set up mother-in-law
style as well
with its own [music] private bath.
Really cool flooring. I haven't seen
that before. almost [music] like mosaic
and a good walk-in closet.
To me, even though they are the same
[music] square footage, I think What do
you think, Raphael? I feel like the last
one felt a little bit bigger and I think
a lot of that has to do with you you
lose
some space here with that formal dining
space and that additional half bath.
But we'll step outside into the outdoor
space.
Different shaped lot, but still super
huge.
A ability to put in your pool. Enjoy all
the shading of these trees. [music]
Super quiet out here.
It will be fully solded and irrigated.
And another gorgeous outdoor kitchen
space with that leather granite
space for your gas grill there. So, it's
going to be propane out propane for the
gas and also [music]
um septic. So, you're on septic out here
on these large lots. If you have any
questions about septic or that's
concerning to you, it's actually really
common, especially on these larger lots.
but not city sewer. You have city water
and other city utilities. Okay, but
leave a note below. Did you like number
one, the Hoover floor plan, or did you
like number two, this Castell? [music]
And don't forget, these are the speck
homes. Those are those prices you there
are still buildable lots. So, if you're
curious on building new construction or
looking at the speck home inventory and
the different ways I can help negotiate
for you, you [music] know where to find
me. All my contact information is below.
Okay. Hey, I hope you love this tour of
Rancho Delago within Morgan's [music]
Point Resort, Belton ISD. It's one of my
favorite communities. I'm sure you can
see why everything is so pretty out
[music] here. If you would like more
information on this community or just
living in central Texas in general, I'd
love to be your go-to resource. [music]
Till next time, I'm Andrea Dudick, your
local real estate broker and relocation
guide.